# Sinclair Akoto London | 07481790498

#### Summary

I am capable, enthusiastic and confident individual, with strong interpersonal & communication skills. Computer literate and self-motivated, with a committed and hardworking approach. Able to work under pressure and to tight deadlines, both on own initiative and in a team environment, with proven experience in a corporate office environment. Excellent attention to detail coupled with strong organisation skills

#### **Kev Skills**

- Pvthon & Flask
- SQL PostgresSQL, MvSQL
- Git / Bash
- Heroku server
- Data collation
- Attention to detail
- Highly self motivated but also a team player
- Highly self motivated, can also work well in a team.
- Willingness to learn and adapt
- Always thinking of new ideas.
- 2 vears development experience

### **Kev Achievements**

- The confidence to find a solution when I come across bug errors and other discrepancies. Due to
  my high use of trail and error when coding, it may sometimes take me a while to solve a problem
  within a code. However, I do not see this as a disadvantage, but rather an advantage where I am
  taking a detailed approach to find a solution and remembering how to remedy it when a resolution is found.
- Built my first program in under 6 weeks. This program is called EasyCHEF! and it is deployed locally from my laptop.
- EasyCHEF! is a simple program that uses dictionaries, lists and functions to complete its objectives
- EasyCHEF! prompts the user to select one ingredient from a list of proteins, carbohydrates & vegetables. The program then searches for the matching 3 ingredients given to its recipes in it's foodbank, and returns a recipe once a match is found. If the user does NOT like the first choice, they can prompt the program to find a different recipe but with the same 3 main ingredients.
- I plan to build this into a web app once I broaden my skill set

This EasyCHEF! web is slightly different; it uses an API to retrieve a recipe then display only the name of recipe, cooking method and web page back to the user. I will test different ways how my web app can interact with API's to produce a more detailed & intricate search for recipes. You can view the code for the web app on GitHub.

• Feedback Forms: Developed a feedback form for a shisha bar/restaurant (Aurous79). The (previous) owner at the time wanted a way to collect customers' details by giving them discounts on their bills as an incentive. I suggested a feedback form where he could ask questions related to his business/customer service, and also gain the opportunity to collate customer information. Once they enter their details (such as name

& email), they will receive an automated email once the feedback form has been completed. The owners can then log into the admin page with their username & password, and run a report with the information given, and harvest their customer information for future promotions & advertising.

- The information is stored into a database and then reloaded back onto the HTML page for the user to see.
- You can view my code on GitHub. This uses an SQLite3 database which can be run from your local computer. You can test out the Aurous79 Feedback Form online. This uses a PostgreSQL database which is connected to the app through a remote server online.
   Sorry, the online version is still under construction...
- Spreadsheet Compiler: Built a Jobs Log which is an app that easily helps the user to compile information into one spreadsheet. This Jobs Log has a row of columns that the user fills in (in this case an Audio Visual department); when the log is submitted it is stored into a (remote PostgreSQL) database and then uploaded back onto the same page. Every new log entered creates a new row in the table below. The AV department can then run reports from the different columns (such as the type of job and the outcome of each job).
- You can view my code on GitHub.
   You can test out the Jobs Log online.
  - Visitor Log In System
  - Signup/Create Profile platform where users can create their own profile (if they
    don't already have one) in order to gain access to a page.
  - A Booking System book classes at a gym
  - Shopping Page the ability to add items in a basket and give the total cost to the user. Also redirect page to a **secure** payment system.
  - An extension of the Jobs Log where I would house many different departments under one site. Each colleague would choose which department they work in, enter their unique password in order to gain access to their spreadsheet.
- Built my first online webpage. This page was a simple page which tested out the bare bones basics (which I needed). The page has three links; the first link directs you to a page to view entries in a (PostgreSQL) database. The second link directs you to a page with an image embedded in the background. The main task was to connect my web app to the database on the remote server and then display the data back onto the page. Once this worked, this allowed me to redevelop my offline apps and post them online.
- You can view my code on GitHub. You can test the web app online.

#### Education

2008 – 2010Manchester Metropolitan University – Film & Television Broadcast Media

2006 – 2008Stockport College

1998 – 2003Wright Robinson Sports College

8 GCSE's (Maths, English Literature, English Language, Double Award Science)

## **Qualifications**

SIA Door Supervision & CCTV badge Foundation Degree in Film & Broadcast Media

National Diploma in Media: Moving Images

#### **Employment History**

### Security Officer - Deloitte - London

August 2018 to Present

- Access control, concierge service, interior patrols, ensuring public safety.
- Floor walking
- Incident reporting
- Ensuring team members are allocated in correct positions

#### Security Officer - Willis Towers Watson - London

April 2016 to August 2018

#### Responsibilities

Access control, CCTV patrols, interior & exterior patrols, Control Room duties, hotel concierge service, customer service, ensuring public safety.

#### Accomplishments

Cover supervisor role & training new operatives on site.

#### Skille Heed

Paying attention to detail, working as an individual or as part of a team, communication, organisation & time keeping are essential in the security industry - as this could affect other colleagues if high standards are not kept.

## **Lighting Technician (Spark)**

Film Freelancer - London

May 2010 to Present

Responsibilities

Setting up lighting equipment on a film set, creating character and dimension to the scene. Making sure the lighting set up is safe and not hazardous for any other film crew staff on set. Making sure the job is quickly and safely completed.

#### Accomplishments

Producing creativity into the film set, adhering to a deadline.

#### Skills Used

Being able to work with a large amount of people from different backgrounds/cultures, working individually to effectively get the job done as a team, product knowledge, communication skills and being able to think on my feet are essential for my job role.

#### Interpersonal Skills

I have good communication skills; some natural and some gained through my studies and supporting my-self from an early age.

### **Hobbies and Interests**

I like to exercise and study more about Python & Flask in my spare time.

### References available on request.